Kathy Jakobsen Papers 2006.0245
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Kathy Jakobsen Papers
undated, 1978-2005
2006.0245
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
17.7 Linear feet
Jakobsen is one of America's premier folk artists. Her paintings are part of a number of permanent collections, including those of the Museum of American Folk Art and the Smithsonian. She is well known as a book illustrator for such titles as "Johnny Appleseed" (1990) and "This Land is Your Land"(1998) and has authored and illustrated two books, "My New York"(1993) and "Meet me in the Magic Kingdom"(1995). This collection houses: artwork, audio visual materials, books, color slides, correspondence, drawings, illustrations, photographs, posters, publications, sketches, and videocassettes.
Jakobsen, Kathy
General note
Published Works: Johnny Appleseed(1990), My New York(1993), Meet me in Magic Kingdom(1995), This Land is you Land(by Woodie Guthrie, 1998).
Scope and Content
The collection contains the correspondence, posters, sketches, books, publications, and illustrations of folk artist Kathy Jakobsen. Publications include post cards, bookmarks, calendars, and copies of "Horizon - The Magazine of the Arts", "New York Promenade", and "Folk Art - Magzine of the Museum of American Folk art", which contain her illustrations.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in a single series.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Dodd
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by Kathy Jakobsen on August 18, 2006.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Jakobsen, Kathy; Audio visual materials.; Books.; Color slides.; Correspondence.; Illustrations (visual works).; Photographs.; Posters.; Publications.; Sketches.; Videocassettes.; Works of Art.
- Series I: Inventory, undated, 1978-2005
  - Publications, 1981-2006 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    [Subjects include: postcards published by the Museum of American Folk Art, bookmarks published by Connecticut Library Consortium, calendars published by Americana Gallery, calendars published by Woody Land, calendars published by American Folk Art, Horizon — The Magazine of the Arts December 1981, September and October 1982), New York Promenade (October 1981-March 1982), calendars published by American Kitchen, calendars published by Folk Art, 1990 National Christmas Pageant of Peace, The Fairfield County Times (December 1998), Folk Art — Magazine of the Museum of American Folk Art (1987-1989, 1990-1994, 1998-2000).]
  - Publications, photographs, correspondence, manuscripts, undated, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
    [Subjects include: Tom Sawyer land, Haunted Mansion Extension, Spectro Magic Parade, Main Street (Don’t need), Splash Mountain, The Swiss Family Tree House, Endpapers and Mickey’s room, Disney buildings and the Sea World, Left side of the Main Street, the rest of the Disneyland, Disney Diary and materials, Disney Trip — Amtrak, The Miracle of the Hub, Correspondence 1989-1990, Disneyland, Disneyland Maps, Press, Magazines, Brochures.]
  - Publications, ephemera, undated, 1990-2003 (Box 3)
    [Subjects include: Johnny Appleseed, My New York and book covers, Meet Me in the Magic Kingdom, Westport— The Magazine Serving Fairfield, Weston and Westport (December 1998), Weston Holiday Book (2003), Country Home (April 1990), Décor (July 1995, July 1997), Innocence of Vision, The Shakers and the World’s People, pages of various magazines illustrated by Jakobsen, American Folk Art of the Twentieth Century, postcards for The Shakers and the World’s People, House on Barnum Street, Apple Picking, Noah’s Ark, Circus Parade, Frank J. Miele Galler, and many other postcards, Good Living, gift bags that Jakobsen designed and published by Bloomingdale’s, paper bags from Tokyo Disney.]
  - Drawings, photographs, publications, manuscripts, undated, 1978-2005 (Box 4)
    [Subjects include: Disney Book, Sketches, pages of magazines, photographs, and brochures from the Disney World that Kathy collected as resources for her work, child’s drawing of Kathy Jakobsen, photographs from Woody’s 90th birthday party, Rizzoli New York (1983), Museum (1985), The Clarion (1978, 1981, 1986, 1988, 1992), Guthrie Awards Dinner (2202, 2005), Photographs from Guthrie Awards Dinner, Prints from Slides for Walt Disney World, papers for Johnny Appleseed.]
  - Photographs, illustrations, publications, undated, 1983-2005 (Box 5)
    [Subjects include: Disney--Pirates of the Caribbean, Reunion, Adventureland — Animals, Small World Area, Frontierland, Title Page, Mickey Mania Parade, Horse Main Street, Country Bear Jamboree, Liberty Square — Hall of Presidents, Train Station, Disneyland magazine (1983, 1989, 1990, 1994, 2004, 2005), Disneyland Inside Story, The Pacific States—California, Oregon and Washington, A Pictorial History of American Mining from Pre-Columbian Time to the Present Day, My New York —New Anniversary Edition.]
  - Posters, publications, moving images, realia, undated, 1981-2005 (Box 6)
    [Subjects include: Winter-theme posters, Johnny Appleseed 3 copies, 1 in Japanese), calendars published by Folk Art, Bits and Pieces Puzzle, 2 boxes of Bunka with Flair, Video tape for Attractions—Marketing Mickey Mania Town Square, 70-piece jigsaw puzzle, Disney Press (Fall 2005), Artexpo New York, Country Home (1987, 1993), Flatiron News, Horizon (October 1981), Colonial Homes (1982), Folk Art (2001, 2003), postcards published by Connecticut Library consortium.]
  - Manuscripts, publications, correspondence, undated (Box 7)
    [Subjects include: My New York, This land is your land.]
  - Posters, fliers, administrative records, notes, ephemera, clippings, awards, transcripts, books, 1986-2001 (Box 8)
    [Subjects include: Courteous Connecticut, Bridgeport Salutes Liberty, U.S. House of Representatives.]
  - Posters, works of art, undated (Oversize 1)
    [Subjects include: Times Square: 1904-2004, “Sharpen Your Wits” and “Shakers.”]
  - Posters, works of art, undated, 1989 (Oversize 2)
    [Subjects include: New Hampshire, Virginia, Maryland, Barnum Festival.]
  - Correspondence, Notes, Photographic negatives, Transparencies, Works of art, undated (Box 9)
    Scope and Content Note
    [Subjects include: Negatives of photographs and transparencies taken at Disney World for research, .]